const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",a="crk",o=200,i=120,t=[{id:501,question:"“I tell you, if these were silent, the very stones would cry out.” Jesus’ statement above was made when",option:{a:"He was rebuked by the Pharisees for eating with sinners",b:"the scribes and the chief priest came to arrest Him",c:"He consoled a woman on His way to the cross",d:"the Pharisees asked Him to rebuke His disciples"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:294,question:"According to Prophet Jeremiah, one of the promises of God was that He would give the Israelites",option:{a:"new priests",b:"new commandments",c:"kings after His own heart",d:"shepherds after His own heart."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:793,question:"  The wife of  Moses was called   ",option:{a:"Rebecca",b:"Rachel",c:"Zipporah",d:"Deborah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:56,question:"He shall save his people from their sins. Who is being referred to here? ",option:{a:"John the Baptist ",b:"Elijah ",c:"Elisha ",d:"Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:291,question:"Prophet Amos told Israel to hate evil, love good and establish justice in the gate so that God would",option:{a:"heal their diseases",b:"give them good leaders",c:"be gracious to them",d:"multiply their descendants."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:328,question:"‘Blessed are you, Simon Bar-Jona ! For flesh and blood has not revealed this to you...’ As exemplified by the statement above, for believers to be able to identify with Jesus, they must",option:{a:"offer their lives",b:"be led by the Spirit",c:"keep all the commandments",d:"vow not to deny Him."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:247,question:"In Timothy, Paul urges Christians to pray for kings and those in authority for the achievement of",option:{a:"a successful Christian life",b:"godly and acceptable life",c:"peace and exaltation in life",d:"quiet and peaceable life."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:653,question:"The sons of Eli were regarded as worthless men for all the following reasons except",option:{a:"sleeping with the women at the tent of meeting",b:"failing to attend the places of worship regularly.",c:"taking the meat for sacrifice before boiling.",d:"showing no respect for God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:51,question:"Name three places Christian religious people look up to find the truth about the nature of God",option:{a:"In the sacred scripture ",b:"In the religious leader ",c:"In the church ",d:"In their conscience."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:20,question:"Who was authorized by God to go and liberate the Israelites the Egyptian bondage? ",option:{a:"Joshua ",b:"Daniel ",c:"Solomon ",d:"Moses."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:639,question:"Paul in Corinthians advised that Christians should re-affirm their love for those who",option:{a:"are kind to them",b:"wrong them",c:"humble themselves",d:"are in authority."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:313,question:"During Jehoiakim’s reign, Judah was destroyed as punishment for Manasseh’s sin of",option:{a:"keeping Temple prostitutes in the land",b:"defiling the vessels in the Temple",c:"offering unacceptable sacrifice",d:"shedding innocent blood."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:1001,question:"“...Behold, to obey is better than sacrifice and to hearken than the fat of rams”. This statement was Samuel’s reaction to ",option:{a:"David’s defence of his sin",b:"Saul’s defence of disobedience. ",c:"King Agag’s defence of his victory",d:"Eli’s defence of the sins of his sons."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:898,question:"Who among the following was to ensure the safety of King Saul in the wilderness of Ziph? ",option:{a:"Joab           ",b:"Jonathan          ",c:"Abner           ",d:"  Abimelech"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:137,question:"“God has given your enemy into your hand this day, now, therefore, let me pin him to the earth with one stroke of the spear, and I will not strike him twice”. This statement was made to David by",option:{a:"Abishai ",b:"Abner    ",c:"Ahimelech ",d:"David’s armour bearer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:25,question:"The person who the Bible calls the son of consolation is ",option:{a:"Barsabas ",b:"Barabbas ",c:"Barnabas ",d:"Bathsheba"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:781,question:"Herod Agrippa persecuted Peter primarily to______",option:{a:"contain the news about Jesus' resurrection",b:"signal to the Apostles that he wouldn't tolerate them",c:"obstruct the spread of the gospel",d:"please the Jews"},section:"",image:"",answer:" d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:917,question:"In his Transfiguration, Jesus took with him ",option:{a:"Peter, James and Andrew. ",b:"Andrew, Peter and John. ",c:"Matthew, James and Peter. ",d:"James, John and Peter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:195,question:"“O dry bones, hear the word of the Lord… “The dry bones mentioned by Prophet Ezekiel  in the statement above refer to the",option:{a:"Amalakite king and soldiers  ",b:"Whole house of Israel  ",c:"Hittites and the Assyrians  ",d:"Babylonians troubling Israel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:526,question:"“The Son of man must suffer many things, and be rejected by the elders .....” Jesus made the statement above after He",option:{a:"cleansed the Temple",b:"demanded to know who people thought He was",c:"taught on the Mount",d:"was asked by Pilate if He was the King of the Jews"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:643,question:"Paul in Thessalonians told believers that the coming of the Lord would be accompanied by",option:{a:"songs of praise",b:"the sound of the trumpet",c:"signs and wonders",d:"wailing and mourning"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:441,question:"When Christians give freely, God will supply",option:{a:"only for those that give",b:"their needs according to His riches in glory",c:"their needs according to the measure they give",d:"their needs day by day."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:792,question:"Which of the following rivers flowed out of Eden to water ",option:{a:"Abana            ",b:" Pharpar              ",c:"Pishon             ",d:"Nile"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:645,question:"Peter in his epistle enjoined servants to be sub¬missive to their masters with all",option:{a:"gentleness",b:"seriousness",c:"respect",d:"humility."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:52,question:"Explain why Jesus was identified as the lamb by John (Jn:1:29 ) ",option:{a:"lamb of God is a figurative language which describes Christ sacrificial mission in the word ",b:"he is being compared to the Passover Lamb that would atone for the sins of all world ",c:"Because the lamb is attentive to his owner ",d:"it shows patience, meekness, gentleness and innocence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:687,question:"‘Death is swallowed up in victory, “oh death, where is your victory”? This statement is found in the book of",option:{a:"Corinthians.",b:"Romans.",c:"Galatians.",d:"Philemon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:89,question:"‘Now I known that Lord has sent his angel to deliver me ……”who said this? ",option:{a:"Joseph ",b:"Moses ",c:"Paul ",d:"Peter "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:222,question:"Abiding in Christ’s love demands that we",option:{a:"have hope for the future",b:"keep His commandments",c:"imitate one another",d:"manifest the peace of God"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:407,question:"Solomon’s wisdom surpassed the wisdom of all the people of the East and all wisdom of Egypt because he",option:{a:"prayed and fasted daily",b:"employed the service of seers",c:"judged difficult cases",d:"got his wisdom from God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:423,question:"“Lord, if you will, you can make me clean.” The statement above was made by the",option:{a:"leper",b:"paralytic",c:"centurion servant",d:"epileptic boy."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:309,question:"Solomon made the most unwise decision by engaging in",option:{a:"marriages to foreign women",b:"alliances with his brothers",c:"so many wars of conquest",d:"developmental works."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:1057,question:"Gehazi became a leper because of his",option:{a:"deceitfulness   ",b:"greed    ",c:"wickedness         ",d:"lies"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:475,question:"The treasures which Jesus wants us to lay in heaven include",option:{a:"generosity and kindness.",b:"love and mercy.",c:"works of righteousness",d:"gold and silver."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:400,question:"Moses ran away from Egypt after killing an Egyptian because he felt that he might be",option:{a:"endangering other Israelites by his actions",b:"killed by the Egyptian mob",c:"imprisoned by the Egyptian security officers",d:"killed by Pharaoh of Egypt."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:871,question:"In the garden of Gethsemane, Jesus",option:{a:"was arrested",b:"was crucified",c:"rebuked Judas Iscariot",d:"prayed for peace"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:654,question:"Who was the first king of Israel?",option:{a:"Kish",b:"David",c:"Solomon",d:"Saul"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:22,question:"Who is an atheist? ",option:{a:"someone who does believe in God ",b:"someone who rejects completely the idea of a divine being ",c:"someone who believes that it is impossible to know if there is God or not ",d:"someone who abuses religious people."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:464,question:"Jeremiah said the people of Judah were in a state of mourning because,",option:{a:"they sinned against God.",b:"their vessels were empty",c:"their farms were destroyed.",d:"there was drought in the land."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:340,question:"In Corinthians, believers are taught to forgive one another in order to",option:{a:"keep Satan from gaining advantage",b:"prevent the wrongdoer from losing his salvation",c:"remove the curse from the offender",d:"discourage the offender from committing more sin."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:106,question:"The sun stood still when ",option:{a:"Moses led the Israelites out of Egypt ",b:"Jericho fell to the army of Joshua ",c:"Noah came out of the ark ",d:"Joshua defeated the Amorites at Gideon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:951,question:"Asa is an example of a parent",option:{a:"who failed to direct his children’s path. ",b:"who admonished his children.",c:"whose children perverted justice",d:"whose children interfered with God’s sacrifice"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:753,question:"One of the most significant lessons from the healing of the Centurion's Servant is that ____________",option:{a:"Jesus has the power to forgive sins",b:"The Level of faith of the servant made Jesus heal him",c:"The Salvation of God is universal",d:"Even the sons of the Kingdom are not worthy of God's Kingdom"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:416,question:"Before his call, Amos was a",option:{a:"herdsman",b:"seer",c:"farmer",d:"prophet."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:846,question:"The minority report of the twelve spies was presented by",option:{a:"Caleb and Joshua",b:"Palti and Gaddiel",c:"Joshua and Ammiel",d:"Sethur and Gaddiel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:754,question:"Josiah sent _____the priest to inquire of the Lord from Huldah",option:{a:"Shallim",b:"Huldah",c:"Hilkiah",d:"Shapham"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:306,question:"The punishment for Adam and Eve’s sin was that they",option:{a:"were driven out of the garden",b:"would be naked forever",c:"would never fellowship with God",d:"would be enemies of crawling animals."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:661,question:"“Your father made our yoke heavy. Now therefore, lighten the hard service of your father.” These were the words of",option:{a:"Jeroboam",b:"Solomon",c:`.         
David`,d:"Ahijah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:323,question:"‘Follow me and leave the dead to bury their own dead’ By this statement, Jesus means that",option:{a:"disciples shall not attend burials",b:"there is no life after death",c:"following Him comes before anything else",d:"shall leave their families in God’s care"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:579,question:"The conversion of the Ethiopian eunuch confirms the",option:{a:"universality of the gospel.",b:"work of the Apostles.",c:"work of Philip in Samaria",d:"the love of God for the eunuch."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:583,question:"Why according to Paul must Christians be subject to civil authority?",option:{a:"To receive God’s approval",b:"To avoid God’s wrath",c:"God has commanded it",d:"It is an Old Testament law"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:252,question:"In his teaching on partiality, James declares that mercy triumphs over",option:{a:"judgment",b:"righteousness",c:"grace",d:"faith."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:745,question:"St. Paul's teaching on forgiveness primarily shows that________",option:{a:"Subordinates must regard their superiors and vice-versa for forgiveness to thrive",b:"Genuine forgiveness only comes from God",c:"Christians must not institute a 'Master-Servant' relationship contract",d:"Philemon had unilaterally decided not to accept Onesimus back"},section:"",image:"",answer:" a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:806,question:"Which of  the following prophets taught that Yahweh was merciful",option:{a:" Isaiah          ",b:" Hosea             ",c:"Amos        ",d:"Ezekiel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:760,question:"The intent of the their temptation of Christ was to_____________",option:{a:"Make him focus on wordly possessions",b:"Make him a political Messiah",c:"Make him seem like a Magician",d:"Make him see the riches of the world from a high mountain"},section:"",image:"",answer:" a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:64,question:"Israel went into Assyrain captivity in ",option:{a:"71AD ",b:"720BC ",c:"722BC ",d:"68AD"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:269,question:"The disciple who replaced Judas Iscariot was",option:{a:"Justus",b:"Stephen",c:"Mathias",d:"Luke."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:673,question:"The Jews showed their hatred for Paul and Barnabas in Pisidia by",option:{a:"dragging out the apostles for stoning.",b:"insisting and driving them out of the Synagogue.",c:"influencing leading men in the city to drive them out.",d:"beating and stoning them in the Synagogue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:145,question:"The Amalekites who opposed the Israelites in the wilderness were from the lineage of  ",option:{a:"Benjamin ",b:"Jacob ",c:"Esau ",d:"Reuben"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:330,question:"The tearing of the curtain of the Temple into two at the death of Jesus signifies",option:{a:"the passing away of the prophets",b:"direct access to God through Christ",c:"that Jesus was a powerful person",d:"that God was truly with Jesus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:239,question:"Which of the following does not relate to the new life in Christ?",option:{a:"Baptism",b:"Circumcision",c:"Grace of God",d:"Faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:1063,question:"The indigenous official of King Darius were unhappy with Daniel because he ",option:{a:"often reported them to the King ",b:"was a Jewish exile         ",c:" had an excel lent spirit ",d:"refused to worship the golden image"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:491,question:"According to Paul in Romans, if it is the adherents of the law who are to be the heirs of Abraham then faith in Jesus is",option:{a:"null and void.",b:"not attainable",c:`.     			
beyond the reach of Gentiles`,d:"transgression of the law."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:542,question:"“........ I am the Lord, and there is no other, besides me 	there is no God....” God’s statement above through Isaiah depicts",option:{a:"assurance to Isaiah of His existence",b:"Israel’s acceptance of His Supremacy",c:"His divine nature",d:"His sovereignty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:982,question:"James teaches that all the following are true causes of unanswered prayers except ",option:{a:"sin",b:"diligence",c:"unfaithfulness",d:"greed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:926,question:"Philip’s flight into Samaria was necesitated by ",option:{a:"the need to convert the Samarians. ",b:"directive from the Holy Spirit. ",c:"persecution of Christians by Saul.",d:"the stoning of Stephen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:580,question:"After his conversion, Paul was introduced to the disciples in Jerusalem by",option:{a:"Peter",b:"Ananias.",c:"Barnabas.",d:"Philip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:296,question:"“Test your servants for ten days; let us be given vegetables to eat and water to drink...” In the statement above, Daniel was talking to",option:{a:"King Darius",b:"the chief of the eunuchs",c:"the steward of the chief eunuch.",d:"King Artaxerxes."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:389,question:"In Romans, Paul taught that where there is no law, there is no",option:{a:"transgression",b:"peace",c:"reward",d:"punishment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:53,question:"Who do people say the son of man is? Jesus asks this question to know people’s ",option:{a:"desire ",b:"demand ",c:"mind ",d:"pinion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:17,question:"“I am to be gathered to my fathers; bury me with my fathers” (Gen 49:29) Who was the speaker? ",option:{a:"Joseph ",b:"Jacob ",c:"Job ",d:"James"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:584,question:"In the Epistle to the Romans, justification is received through",option:{a:"faith in Jesus.",b:"moral uprightness",c:"observance of the law.",d:"giving of alms"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:630,question:"The message of the risen Christ to the women who came early to the tomb was to be relayed to the disciples and (Mark 16:7)",option:{a:"the Jews",b:"the Sadducees",c:"Thomas",d:"Peter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:954,question:"The worship of “Host of Heaven” in Judah during Manasseh’s reign was an indication that",option:{a:"Yahweh’s worship had decline",b:"Judah’s king was weak",c:"Assyrian influence was strong. ",d:"Babylonian influence was great"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:473,question:"“And if anyone will not receive you or listen to your words, shake off the dust from your feet as you leave that house.” This is a sign of",option:{a:"forgiveness",b:"rebuke",c:"acceptance",d:"condemnation."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:500,question:"Paul in Romans said that the righteousness of God has been manifested through faith in Jesus Christ for",option:{a:"the exaltation of the authority",b:"the cleansing of the sinners",c:"the dead in Christ",d:"all those who believe"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:514,question:"“Shall l pursue after this band? Shall l overtake them?” David’s dependence on God for direction is depicted in the statement above when",option:{a:"Absalom had revolted against him",b:"Saul was within his grasp",c:"the Amalekites had raided Ziklag",d:"he was to go against Goliath"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:308,question:"Saul’s decision to consult a medium displayed his lack of",option:{a:"faith in his army",b:"faith in God",c:"leadership qualities",d:"respect for the dead."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:561,question:"Which of the following prophets taught that Yahweh was merciful?",option:{a:"Isaiah",b:"Hosea",c:"Amos",d:"Ezekiel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:665,question:"God’s constant love for unfaithful Israel is demonstrated in the book of",option:{a:"Amos",b:"Isaiah",c:"Hosea",d:"Ezekiel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:782,question:'"Hosanna to the son of David! Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord, Hosanna in the highest!" This was... account of the Triumphal Entry',option:{a:"Luke's",b:"Mark's",c:"Matthew's",d:"John's"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:554,question:"When Abner wanted to transfer his allegiance to David, the latter gave him the condition to",option:{a:"openly submit to Joab.",b:"convince all Israel to come over to David.",c:"restore his wife Michal to him.",d:"slay Ishbosheth. Saul’s successor."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:339,question:"According to Paul in Philippians, humility means giving consideration to other people’s",option:{a:"wealth",b:"weakness",c:"interests",d:"needs."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:297,question:"God blessed and hallowed the seventh day because",option:{a:"it was the day He rested from creation",b:"it was the day He created man",c:"He wanted it to be a day of worship",d:"He saw that all He had created was good."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:117,question:"Paul was accused of apparently being a preacher of foreign divinities in Athens because he preached Jesus and the ",option:{a:"Cross ",b:"Law ",c:"resurrection ",d:"second coming"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:179,question:"Who among the seven deacons was an evangelist  who had four daughters who prophesied?  ",option:{a:"Stephen  ",b:"Philip   ",c:"Barnabas   ",d:"Nicholas"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:969,question:" Before His ascension the apostles asked Jesus, “Lord will you at this time restore the kingdom to Israel?” This implies that",option:{a:"some apostles wanted posts in Jesus’ government. ",b:"the zealots were ready to attack the Romans",c:"Jesus was misunderstood as a political Messiah. ",d:"Jesus’ plans were not known to them."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:1085,question:"James advised against looking down on the poor because they are",option:{a:"the rightful heirs of the kingdom ",b:"those who spent time on the Lord",c:"for peace and self sacrifice",d:"those who contribute little but do a lot"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:46,question:"Which of the following prophets was described as weeping prophet? ",option:{a:"Amos ",b:"Ezekiel ",c:"Jeremiah ",d:"Zephaniah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:989,question:"Which of Paul’s epistle was written to an individual?",option:{a:"Romans ",b:"Corinthians   ",c:"Colossians    ",d:"Philemon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:728,question:"Peter healed Aeneas who had been bedridden for ____ years?",option:{a:"Four",b:"Six",c:"Eight",d:"Twelve"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:734,question:"The accusation of blasphemy against Moses, the law and God was levied against _______",option:{a:"Stephen",b:"Peter and John",c:"Paul",d:"Philip"},section:"",image:"",answer:" a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:992,question:"Moses was bom at a period when the Hebrews were",option:{a:"suffering.   ",b:".   increasing",c:"backsliding",d:"rejoicing."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:539,question:"Paul returned Philemon’s slave back to him, to ensure that",option:{a:"Philemon forgave and accepted the slave",b:"the slave can complete his service time",c:"he would be welcome when he left prison",d:"he could boast of Philemon’s obedience"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:290,question:"Immediately after the contest on Mount Carmel, Elijah prayed and God answered him with",option:{a:"thunder",b:"rainfall",c:"a whirlwind",d:"a heavy storm."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:232,question:"Paul argued that Jesus died for us while we were yet sinners in order to",option:{a:"prove that he was not an ordinary man",b:"show Gods’ love for sinful man",c:"warn us to desist from sin",d:"give us power to possess the earth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:456,question:"David showed Nathan the prophet that he had repented of his sin by",option:{a:"refusing to marry Uriah’s wife.",b:"confessing that he had sinned.",c:"offering to compensate Uriah’s family",d:"making sacrifice to please God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:480,question:"According to John’s Gospel, Lazarus was from",option:{a:"Bethany",b:"Galilee.",c:"Jerusalem.",d:"Bethsaida."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:818,question:"St. John refers to Jesus’ miracles as ‘signs’ because they ",option:{a:"acceptance of Jesus as son of Go ",b:"proofs of the kingdom of Go ",c:"faith in Jesus as the means to eternal life.    ",d:"demand for more wonders"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:1086,question:"As they were sharing Christ’s sufferings, Peter advised Christians to",option:{a:"be prayerful       ",b:"rejoice       ",c:"be trustful ",d:"persevere"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:288,question:"The Kingdom of Israel was divided because the",option:{a:"kingdom was too large to be administered",b:"leadership wanted to create more nations",c:"followership wanted more nations",d:"last two kings made unwise policies."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:366,question:"“Blessed are the peace makers for",option:{a:"theirs is the kingdom of God”",b:"they shall be called sons of God”",c:"they shall inherit the earth”",d:"they shall be comforted”."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:741,question:'"I gave you cleanness of teeth in all your cities". By this statement, God gave them ______',option:{a:"New set of teeth",b:"No food to eat",c:"No water to drink",d:"No teeth at all"},section:"",image:"",answer:" b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:681,question:"The resurrection of Jesus is significant to Christians for it 	marked the",option:{a:"end of the Jewish faith.",b:"assurance of eternal life for Christians.",c:"beginning of Christianity",d:"end of Jesus’ earthly ministry."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:929,question:"Prior to the day of Pentecost, members that constituted the early Church were",option:{a:"120",b:"1,200.00",c:"3,000.00",d:"4,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:1064,question:"“I gave you cleanness of teeth in all your cities” This statement means God gave them",option:{a:"no water to drink ",b:"new set of teeth ",c:"no food to eat                       ",d:"no teeth at all"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:755,question:"St James teaching on impartiality centers on_________",option:{a:"A Giving the place of the rich to the poor and in the church",b:"Loving our neighbours as ourselves in all situation",c:"The rich spending their wealth on the poor for social equity",d:"Christians not being partial to idle people"},section:"",image:"",answer:" b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:133,question:"Who according to James blaspheme the honourable name by which Christians are called",option:{a:"Non believers",b:"Pagan rulers",c:"Antichrists",d:"Rich people"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:988,question:"The meaning of Reconciliation in Paul’s thought is how to",option:{a:"pay back your debt",b:"have peace with God and man",c:"give alms to the needy",d:"please God with your prayers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:764,question:"Cleopas' heart burnt within him on the road to Emmaus when Jesus ________",option:{a:"Appeared to them",b:"Broke bread with them",c:"Taught them the scriptures",d:"Walked with them"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:350,question:"What was Moses’ reaction when God called him to liberate his people from Egypt?",option:{a:"He was afraid of being punished for his previous offence",b:"His people would think he was too young to lead them",c:"His people would not listen to him",d:"His father in-law would not allow him to go."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:249,question:"According to Ephesians, children who obey their parents in the Lord will",option:{a:"be happy",b:"go to heaven",c:"have long life",d:"be great."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:873,question:"Which of the following incidents occurred during Jesus’ trial before Caiaphas?",option:{a:"The preference of Barabbas to Jesus",b:" The question of payment of tribute",c:"Accusation of Jesus as a rioter",d:"The seeking of false witness against Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:572,question:"By introducing Jesus as the Lamb, John was pointing to",option:{a:"Jesus’ sacrificial death.",b:"Jesus’ miraculous healing.",c:"the Jewish yearly sacrifices.",d:"the priestly function of Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:120,question:"“Blessed be the Lord God of Israel is a hymn of praise by ",option:{a:"the virgin Mary at the Annunciation ",b:"Zachariah at the birth of John the Baptist ",c:"Simeon at the presentation of Jesus in the temple ",d:"Elizabeth at the visit of Mary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:1089,question:"Peter believed that God appreciates and gives credit to servants who",option:{a:"pray without ceasing    ",b:"keep their tongues shut ",c:"fail to honour wicked masters ",d:"suffer for wrongs hot done"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:990,question:"James urged Christians not to be partial but to fulfil the “royal law.” What is the royal law?",option:{a:"You shall not commit adultery",b:"Do good to those who hate you",c:"You should love your neighbour as yourself",d:"Pray for those in authority always"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:836,question:"In Philippians, Paul taught that Jesus’humility and death on the cross earned Him ",option:{a:"salvation for Israel. ",b:"adoption as son of Go ",c:"exaltation as Lord",d:"eternal life in the kingdom"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:802,question:"Solomon told Hiram, King of Tyre, that he had decided to ",option:{a:"the Lord had given him peace and all good things. ",b:"his father, David, never intended to build one",c:"C he wanted to force Hiram to come to his ai",d:"C he wanted to force Hiram to come to his ai"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:100,question:"Deborah was a judge when Israel was under the yoke of ",option:{a:"Moab ",b:"Midian ",c:"Canaan ",d:"Philistine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:1074,question:"Life in the Early Church was characterized by",option:{a:"fasting and almsgiving      ",b:"         prophetic activities ",c:"communal spirit ",d:"        honesty and peace"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"}],s={message:e,subject:a,status:200,total:120,data:t};export{t as data,s as default,e as message,o as status,a as subject,i as total};
